I'm here because I have a very important message:
أنا هنا لأنني أحمل لكم رسالة مهمة جدا
I think we have found
أعتقد أننا وجدنا
the most important factor for success.
أهم عامل من عوامل النجاح
And it was found close to here, Stanford.
وقد أكتشف قريبا من هنا، في ستانفورد
Psychology professor took kids that were four years old
أخذ أستاذ علم النفس مجموعة من الأطفال في الرابعة من عمرهم
and put them in a room all by themselves.
ووضعهم وحدهم في غرفة
And he would tell the child, a four-year-old kid,
ويقول للطفل ذا الـ 4 سنوات
"Johnny, I am going to leave you here with a marshmallow
جوني، سوف أتركك هنا مع هذه الحلوى
for 15 minutes.
لمدة 15 دقيقة
If, after I come back, this marshmallow is here,
إذا عدت ولازالت الحلوى هنا
you will get another one. So you will have two."
سأعطيك ثانية، فتصبح لديك اثنتين
To tell a four-year-old kid to wait 15 minutes
أن تطلب من طفل في الرابعة من عمره الانتظار لمدة 15 دقيقة
for something that they like,
من أجل شيء يحبه
is equivalent to telling us, "We'll bring you coffee in two hours."
يماثل إخبار أحدنا "سوف تحصل على قهوتك بعد ساعتين"ـ
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Exact equivalent.
يماثله تماما
So what happened when the professor left the room?
فماذا حدث عندما ترك الأستاذ الغرفة؟
As soon as the door closed...
بمجرد أن أغلق الباب
two out of three ate the marshmallow.
أكل طفلين من كل ثلاثة الحلوى
Five seconds, 10 seconds, 40 seconds, 50 seconds,
خمس ثواني، 10 ثواني، 40 ثانية، 50 ثانية
two minutes, four minutes, eight minutes.
دقيقتين، أربع دقائق، ثمان دقائق
Some lasted 14-and-a-half minutes.
لقد صمد البعض 14 دقيقة ونصف
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Couldn't do it. Could not wait.
لم يستطيعوا فعلها، لم يتمكنوا من الانتظار
What's interesting is that one out of three
ما يثير الانتباه أن واحد من كل ثلاثة
would look at the marshmallow and go like this ...
سينظر إلى الحلوى و
Would look at it.
ينظر إليها
Put it back.
يعيدها
They would walk around. They would play with their skirts and pants.
يمشي، يلعب ببنطاله
That child already, at four, understood
ذلك الطفل، في الرابعة، فهم
the most important principle for success,
أهم مبدأ للنجاح
which is the ability to delay gratification.
وهو القدرة على تأخير المنافع
Self-discipline:
ضبط النفس
the most important factor for success.
أهم عوامل النجاح
15 years later, 14 or 15 years later,
بعد 15 عام، 14 أو 15 عام لاحقا
follow-up study.
متابعة للدراسة
What did they find?
ماذا وجدوا؟
They went to look for these kids who were now 18 and 19.
ذهبوا ليبحثوا عن أولئك الأطفال وهم الآن 18 و 19
And they found that 100 percent
ووجدوا أن 100% منهم
of the children that had not eaten the marshmallow were successful.
الذين لم يأكلوا الحلوى أصبحوا ناجحين
They had good grades. They were doing wonderful.
درجاتهم جيدة. وأدائهم رائع
They were happy. They had their plans.
كانوا سعداء. كانت لهم خططهم الخاصة
They had good relationships with the teachers, students.
كانت علاقتهم جيدة بالمدرسين والطلاب
They were doing fine.
وكانوا بأفضل حال
A great percentage of the kids that ate the marshmallow,
وغالبية الأطفال الذين أكلوا الحلوى
they were in trouble.
كانوا متعثرين
They did not make it to university.
لم يتمكنوا من دخول الجامعة
They had bad grades. Some of them dropped out.
كانت درجاتهم منخفضة. بعضهم رسب
A few were still there with bad grades.
والبعض الآخر لا يزال موجودا بدرجات ضعيفة
A few had good grades.
وقلة منهم كانت درجاتهم جيدة
I had a question in my mind: Would Hispanic kids
وقد وردني خاطر: هل أطفال الأسبان
react the same way as the American kids?
سيتصرفون بنفس الطريقة التي تصرف بها الأطفال الأمريكيون ؟
So I went to Colombia. And I reproduced the experiment.
فذهبت إلى كولومبيا. واستخدمت نفس الدراسة
And it was very funny. I used four, five and six years old kids.
وقد كان ذلك طريفا. اختبرت أطفال أربع، خمس و ست سنوات
And let me show you what happened.
دعوني أريكم ما حدث
(Spanish) (Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what happened in Colombia?
فماذا حدث في كولومبيا؟
Hispanic kids, two out of three ate the marshmallow;
طفلين من كل ثلاثة أكلا الحلوى
one out of three did not.
واحد من كل ثلاثة لم يفعل
This little girl was interesting;
هذه الطفلة كانت ملفتة
she ate the inside of the marshmallow.
أكلت الحلوى من الداخل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
In other words, she wanted us to think that she had not eaten it, so she would get two.
بمعنى آخر، أرادت أن توهمنا بأنها لم تأكل الحلوى لتأخذ الثانية
But she ate it.
ولكنها أكلتها
So we know she'll be successful. But we have to watch her.
لذا نعلم أنها ستكون ناجحة. ولكن علينا مراقبتها
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
She should not go into banking, for example,
لا يجب أن تعمل في البنوك، على سبيل المثال
or work at a cash register.
أو المحاسبة
But she will be successful.
ولكنها ستنجح
And this applies for everything. Even in sales.
وهذا ينطبق على كل شيء حتى المبيعات
The sales person that --
مندوب المبيعات الذي
the customer says, "I want that." And the person says, "Okay, here you are."
الذي يقول له العميل "أريد هذا". فيقول المندوب "حسننا، ها هو"ـ
That person ate the marshmallow.
ذلك الشخص أكل الحلوى
If the sales person says, "Wait a second.
إذا قال المندوب "إنتظر دقيقة
Let me ask you a few questions to see if this is a good choice."
دعني أطرح عليك بعض الأسئلة لنرى إذا كان ذلك الاختيار مناسبا"ـ
Then you sell a lot more.
حينها تبيع أكثر
So this has applications in all walks of life.
فهذا له تطبيقاته في جميع مجالات الحياة
I end with -- the Koreans did this.
أنهي بأن الكوريين قاموا بهذا
You know what? This is so good
هل تعلمون؟ هذا جيد جدا
that we want a marshmallow book for children.
بحيث اننا نريد كتاب الحلوى للأطفال
We did one for children. And now it is all over Korea.
أنتجنا الكتاب للأطفال. وهو الآن في كل أرجاء كوريا
They are teaching these kids exactly this principle.
إنهم يعلمون الأطفال هذا المبدأ بالضبط
And we need to learn that principle here in the States,
وعلينا تعلم هذا المبدأ في أمريكا
because we have a big debt.
لأننا نحمل مديونيات كبيرة
We are eating more marshmallows than we are producing.
فما نأكله من حلوى أكثر مما ننتجه
Thank you so much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم